Guide to the Frederic Ewen Papers TAM.277
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Frederic Ewen Papers
1915-1988
1940-1970
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Ewen, Frederic, 1899-
Ewen, Alexander
TAM.277
13.75 Linear Feet in fourteen record cartons and 1 folder.
Frederic Ewen was an English professor at Brooklyn College from 1930 until 1952, when he resigned after refusing to cooperate with the House Un-American Activities Committee's investigation of communism in higher education. He then organized theatrical lectures and performances featuring blacklisted actors. These stage, radio and television performances included Ewen's dramatic adaptations of literary classics. Ewen was also the author of several books, including a biography of Bertolt Brecht. The collection contains notes, manuscripts, correspondence, legal documents, clippings and ephemera.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were donated by Alexander Ewen in circa 1999. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1999.003, 1999.007, 1999.009, and NPA.2005.081.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Personal and Legal Papers
Series III: Scripts
Series IV: Writings by Ewen
Series V: Writings by Others
Series VI: Lecture Notes
Series VII: Research Notes
Series VIII: Subject Files
Series IX: Photographs
Series are arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Frederic Ewen (1899-1988) was an author, educator, and champion of the individual's right to self-expression and intellectual freedom. A popular lecturer at Brooklyn College, where he was Professor of English Literature, he dedicated his final book to his former students, who for him had made "teaching a privilege and learning a joy." Dr. Ewen's commitment to freedom of thought, as well as his political activism during the 1930s, led to his becoming a victim of the academic witch hunts of McCarthy Era, and his forced resignation from Brooklyn College in 1952.
Frederic Ewen was born on October 11th, 1899 in Lemberg, Austria, the son of Isaac and Helen (Kramer) Ewen. He was brought by his family to the United States in 1912 and became a naturalized citizen that same year. Ewen grew up in Brooklyn and then attended City College, where he graduated in 1921. He then entered Columbia University, where he received his M.A. in 1925 and his Ph.D. in English and Comparative Literature in 1932. While studying at City College, he began his career as a teacher, with an appointment as an instructor of English in 1923. In 1930 he became assistant professor of English at Brooklyn College.
In addition to his teaching, Dr. Ewen was a noted author. His first book, The Prestige of Schiller in England, was published by the Columbia University Press in 1932. His Bibliography of Eighteenth-Century English Literature was issued by the same publisher in 1935. With his brother David Ewen, he wrote Musical Vienna, published by Whittlesey House in 1939. The Poetry and Prose of Heinrich Heine, by Citadel, followed in 1948.
Within a few years after he joined Brooklyn College's faculty, Dr. Ewen became involved in the two strong political currents of the day, speaking out against the rise of fascism in Europe and against the inequality of suffering during the Great Depression. He became an active member of the Teachers Union, which organized faculty in all the city colleges and sought to end discrimination on city campuses. He was also active in the campaign to support the Spanish Republicans during the Spanish Civil War.
In 1940 the New York State Legislature's Joint Committee to Investigate Procedure and Methods of Allocating State Moneys for Public School Purposes and Subversive Activities, known as the Rapp-Coudert Committee, began to investigate allegations of subversive activities in the City's public schools and colleges. Along with seven other teachers from Brooklyn College, Dr. Ewen refused to testify publicly before the panel; in private testimony he called the investigation an "attack on the things that the system stands for and had fought in the last 20 years to obtain." Although Dr. Ewen and the Brooklyn College professors were spared the fate suffered by their colleagues at City College who were investigated by the committee--and dismissed by their school--Dr. Ewen and the other progressive teachers at Brooklyn could not escape a renewed assault during the McCarthy Era. After refusing to cooperate with the McCarran Committee in 1952, Dr. Ewen accepted early retirement and a small pension rather than be fired from Brooklyn College. The loss of his teaching position at the early age of 53 was a bitter blow, as he had dedicated his life to his students.
He married Miriam Gideon, a composer and an adjunct professor at Brooklyn College, in 1949. She lost her Brooklyn position in 1954. Frederick Ewen began to organize lectures and readings in union halls, theaters, and other venues. Gathering a team of blacklisted actors who were also in need of work, among them Ossie Davis, Ruby Dee, and John Randolph, Ewen lectured on literature and drama, and the actors would read excerpts from selected works. With Phoebe Brand and John Randolph, Ewen adapted James Joyce's novel, A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man, which was then produced off-Broadway at the Martinique Theater from 1962-1963. Other adaptations with Brand and Randolph include Thomas Mann's "Magic Mountain," produced at Brandeis University in 1967. Television adaptations by Dr. Ewen include "Two Jewish Stories" in 1966, the "Unknown Chekhov" in 1967, and Chekhov's "Ward Number 6" in 1968, all for CBS.
In 1967, Citadel Press published Dr. Ewen's very highly regarded Bertolt Brecht: His Life, His Art, and His Times. He then began to work on his most ambitious project, a three-volume review of the literature and politics of the mid-nineteenth century entitled A Half-Century of Greatness, the first volume, Heroic Imagination: The Creative Genius of Europe from Waterloo to the Revolution of 1848, was published by Citadel in 1984. In October of 1988, Citadel published The Collected Short Stories of Maxim Gorky, which featured an introduction by Dr. Ewen. Shortly before the Gorky book was released, Brooklyn College formally apologized to Dr. Ewen and the other professors dismissed by the college during the McCarthy Era, and in 1988 a lecture series was established at Brooklyn College bearing his name. Frederic Ewen died on October 18, 1988 in Manhattan.
Frederic Ewen Bibliography:
Bertolt Brecht: His Life, His Art, and His Times. New York: Citadel Press, 1967. 573 pp.
Bibliography of Eighteenth-Century English Literature. New York: Columbia University Press, 1935. 28 pp.
Heroic Imagination: the Creative Genius of Europe from Waterloo (1815) to the Revolution of 1848. Secaucus, NJ: Citadel Press, 1984. 742 pp.
Musical Vienna. London: Whittlesey House, 1939. 321 pp.
The Prestige of Schiller in England, 1788-1859. New York: Columbia University Press, 1932. [and New York: AMS Press, 1973]. 287 pp.
The Poetry and Prose of Heinrich Heine, selected and edited with an introduction by Frederic Ewen. New York: Citadel Press: 1948. 874 pp.
Custodial History
The Frederic Ewen Papers were donated in circa 1999 by Alexander Ewen. Included were ten linear feet transferred from Brooklyn College, where they previously had been housed, as well as materials received directly from Alex Ewen. The donation of the Frederic Ewen Papers marked the establishment of the Frederic Ewen Academic Freedom Center at the Tamiment Library, NYU.
Related Materials
American Association of University Professors, Academic Freedom Committee Records (TAM 407)
Frederic Ewen Oral History Collection (OH 52)
Scope and Content Note
The primary focus of the Papers is on Ewen's teaching career at Brooklyn College. A large portion of the papers is comprised of classroom lecture notes and research materials accumulated for Ewen's many books. There are also many annotated play scripts, as well as Ewen's stage adaptations of the literary classics such as Thomas Mann's, Magic Mountain and The Nihilists, inspired by Dostoyeveski's The Possessed. The correspondence is rich with letters written by Ewen's former students upon learning of his departure from Brooklyn College in 1952. There are legal documents ranging from Rapp-Coudert proceedings to actor's contracts for performances through the Master Institute. The collection also contains photographs used in his publications and family photographs.
Civil rights workers |z United States.; Communist teachers.; Anti-communist movements; Manuscripts; Legal documents.; Correspondence.; English literature|x Political aspects.; Communism -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Transcripts.; Notes.; New York (N.Y.).; Dee, Ruby; Ewen, Frederic, 1899-; Ewen, Miriam Gideon; Randolph, John, 1915-2004; Brand, Phoebe, 1907-2004; Davis, Ossie; Teachers' Union of the City of New York; Waterston, Sam; Brooklyn College. Department of English; Citadel Press; New York (State). Legislature. Joint Committee to Investigate Procedure and Methods of Allocating State Moneys for Public School Purposes and Subversive Activities; Ewen, Alexander
- Series I: Correspondence, 1915-1988
  Scope and Content Note
  This series holds correspondence written by Frederic Ewen from 1915 up until his death in 1988. There is a collection of postcards sent to Ewen and his wife Miriam and a few sent from Fred as well-these postcards highlighting various trips to Europe. Also herein are the letters Ewen collected from his former students which shed light on the impact Ewen made in the classroom.
  - Correspondence, 1915-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1956 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and postcards, 1968-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters on Brooklyn College, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - World War II letters from former students, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - World War II letters from former students, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gideon, Miriam (wife), 1926-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Personal and Legal Papers, 1899-1990
  This series consists of various family-related materials including a file relating to Miriam Gideon. This series contains several volumes of Ewen's personal journals and travel logs. It also contains the contracts for Ewen's books, contracts with the actors he hired to perform for his Master Institute and Brooklyn Academy of Music productions, materials related to the Rapp-Coudert Committee and academic freedom (including a transcript of Ewen's testimony), and newspaper articles about the ongoing investigations.
  - Family Files: Birth Certificate and Grade School Report, 1899-1911 (Box Tamiment Shared MSOS003, Folder 1)
  - Family Files: Legal Douments, 1925-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Family Files: Miriam Gideon, 1967, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Family Files: Retirement, 1925-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Family Files: Travel, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1965-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Legal Documents subpoenas and court transcripts, 1940-1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Legal Documents: Actor Contracts, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Legal Documents: Book Contracts, 1942, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee-Academic Freedom Statements made at committee hearings/pamphlets, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Management: Nina Gordani, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1944-1952, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Orphans, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Presidential Citation to Frederic Ewen: Brooklyn College, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series III: Scripts, undated, 1961-1971
  This series is a collection of scripts Ewen used in his classroom and works he used for his stage adaptations; for example, there is a copy of Magic Mountain with Ewen's notes for his own adaptation. There are also scripts for adaptations of works by Ibsen, Aristophanes, Alfred Levinson, and Leo Tolstoy. The adaptations of The Magic Mountain and The Nihilists were done in collaboration with John Randolph and Phoebe Brand.
  - The Keep by Gwyn Thomas, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baruch D'Amsterdam by Henri Sloves, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Phedre by Racine; Oedipus the King by Sophocles, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Nathan the Wise by Gotthold Ephraim Lessing, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Professor Benrhardi by Arthur Schnitzler; The Way of the World by Congreve, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Cave by Edmund B. Hennefeld, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jacob's Dream, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Lesser Ship by Edmund B. Hennefeld, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Man and Superman by George Bernard Shaw, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Loyalties by John Galsworthy, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Look Back, Mrs. Lot-"The Difference" by Ephraim Kishon, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Jewess of Toledo by Franz Grillparzer, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Baal-Shem and the Renegade by Arnold Zweig, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Infernal Machine, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Jew by Richard Cumberland, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Peter Gynt and A Doll's House by Ibsen, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Enemies; Lower Depths; The Miracle at Verdun, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Four-Poster, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Chicken soup with Barley by Arnold Wesker; Egmont by Goethe, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Mandarins; Dance to Death by Emma Lazarus, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Distant Point by Alexander Afinogenov; Untitled, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Awakening of the Prophet, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Edom, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Criminals by Jose Triana; Socrates Wounded by Alfred Levinson; The Chain by Alfred Levinson, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wings Over Europe; As I Lay Dying by William Faulkner, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Frogs by Aristophanes Scenes from Peace by Aristophanes, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Antigone by Anouilh, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Magic Mountain by Thomas Mann, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Vision and Synthesis: The Drama of Chaim Weizmann by Frederic Ewen, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Martin Chuzzlewit by Charles Dickens, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Exodus by Leon Uris, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - No Title, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Love's Labor's Lost by Shakespeare, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - How to Become a Gentleman by Anonymous; Modern Children by Sholom Aleichem, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - My First Day in America by Yuri Suhl; Cowboy on a Wooden Horse by Yuri Suhl; What Happened to My Chicken Liver? by Yuri Suhl, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Love and Intrigue by Fredrich Schiller; Don Carlos by Fredrich Schiller; William Tell by Fredrich Schiller, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Silver Tassie by Sean O'Casey, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Death of Sam, Slaughter House for Fowls, The O'Bannion Scene, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The School for Scandal by Sheridan; Transfiguration by Toller, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Trojan Women by Euripides; Lysistrata by Aristophanes, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Cause of It All by Leo Tolstoy, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Uriel, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Torquato Tasso by Johann Wolfgang von Goethe, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - A Question of Honor by Max Nordau, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Young Hopefuls by Leo Tolstoy; What Men Live By by Leo Tolstoy; The Cause of it All by Leo Tolstoy; Family Happiness by Leo Tolstoy, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Woman Make Trouble from "The Unknown Chekhov"; Polinka Adapted from a story by Anton Chekhov; Two of a Kind by Anton Chekhov; The Bear by Anton Chekhov, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Days of the Commune by Bertolt Brecht, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - An Evening with Anton Chekhov produced by Frederic Ewen, John Randolph and Phoebe Brand [poster], 1961 (Box Tamiment Shared MSOS003, Folder 1)
  - A Tribute to Anton Chekhov adapted by Frederic Ewen, John Randolph and Phoebe Brand, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Unknown Chekhov by Frederic Ewen, Phoebe Brand and John Randolph, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - The Nihilists by Frederic Ewen and John Randolph adapted from Fyodor Dostoyevski's The Possessed, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - The Nihilists by Frederic Ewen and John Randolph adapted from Fyodor Dostoyevski's The Possessed, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - The Magic Mountain adapted by Frederic Ewen and John Randolph, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - The Magic Mountain adapted by Frederic Ewen, Phoebe Brand and John Randolph, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The Magic Mountain adapted by Frederic Ewen, Phoebe Brand and John Randolph, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Magic Mountain adapted by Frederic Ewen, Phoebe Brand and John Randolph, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The Magic Mountain adapted by Frederic Ewen, Phoebe Brand and John Randolph [poster], 1964 (Box Tamiment Shared MSOS003, Folder 1)
- Series IV: Writings by Frederic Ewen, 1915-1989
  The majority of the writings in this series are typescripts of books Ewen published; for example, there is a draft of Heroic Imaginations as well as typescripts of literary works, including The Assassins, The Bridge, The Burning Bush, and A Half Century.
  - The Assassins typescript by Frederic Ewen, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Bridge, A Novel typescript by Frederic Ewen (1 of 5), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Bridge, A Novel typescript by Frederic Ewen (2 of 5), undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Bridge, A Novel typescript by Frederic Ewen (3 of 5), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Bridge, A Novel typescript by Frederic Ewen (4 of 5), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Bridge, A Novel typescript by Frederic Ewen (5 of 5), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The Burning Bush typescript by Frederic Ewen (1 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Burning Bush typescript by Frederic Ewen (2 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Burning Bush typescript by Frederic Ewen (3 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Damaged Archangel typescript by Frederic Ewen, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - A Half Century rejected manuscript by Frederic Ewen, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Heroic Imaginations draft of old manuscript (1 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Heroic Imaginations draft of old manuscript (2 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Heroic Imaginations draft of old manuscript (3 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Maxim Gorkey and his Russia uncorrected and final version, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Walter Pater and the "Worship of Sorrow", 1925 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Articles by Frederic Ewen, 1964, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Short Stories drafts by Frederic Ewen, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Untitled by [Frederic Ewen], undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series V: Writings by others, 1915-1989
  This series is a collection of writings Ewen was either given to look over for critique or works he collected to use in his dramatic productions. There is an untitled piece by Annette Rubinstein, a selection of poems by Sol Chaneles, and other miscellaneous writings.
  - A Footnote to the History of Academic Freedom by Bernard Allen, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 48 Poems by Sol Chaneles, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Writings by Susan Deri, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The History of Tom Jones: A Foundling by Henry Fielding, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Auserwählte Gedichte by William Gutman, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Essays of Elia by Charles Lamb, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - If This is a Man by Primo Levi, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Writings by Eugene Mahon, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Gray's Elegy by Edwin Moise, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Writings by Meyer Reinhold, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Untitled by Annette T. Rubinstein, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Writings by Harry Slochower, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Writings by Alberta B. Szalita M.D., undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Series VI: Lecture Notes, 1918-1966
  This series is arranged alphabetically and contains Ewen's bibliographies, course outlines, exam questions he used at Brooklyn College, and notes from lectures he delivered after leaving his teaching career.
  - Bibliographies (1 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Bibliographies (2 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Bibliographies (3 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Course outlines (1 of 2), 1920s-1940s (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Course outlines (2 of 2), 1920s-1940s (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Course outlines (1 of 2), 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Course outlines (2 of 2), 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Final exam questions, 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Lecture notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Lecture notes: The Aeneid, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Lecture notes: Family in Literature, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Lecture notes: Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man 1962, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Lecture notes: The Tempest, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Literary criticism, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Master Institute, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - News clips, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Notecards, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Programs in German, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series VII: Research Notes, undated
  This series contains research notes Ewen compiled for classroom use, research for his books, and for his dramatic productions. They are arranged by name of author, geographic location, and by subject.
  - Subseries A: Proper Names, undated
    - Arnold, Matthew, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Bakunin, Mikhail, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Baudelaire, Charles, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Bourget, Paul, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Brahms, Johannes- Pianoforte by Dieter Hildebrandt, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Brontës, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Browning, E. B., undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Caryle, Thomas (1 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Caryle, Thomas (2 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Caryle, Thomas (3 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Caryle, Thomas and John Ruskin, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Clough, Arthur Hugh, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor (1 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor (2 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Comte, Auguste and John Stuart Mill (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Comte, Auguste and John Stuart Mill (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Courbet, Gustave, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Darwin, Charles, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Dickens, Charles (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Dickens, Charles (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Eliot, George and G. H. Lewes, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Eliot, T. S., undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Engles, Fredrick and Karl Marx, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Flaubert, Gustave, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Froude, James Anthony- The Nemesis of Faith, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Gay, Peter- The Tender Passion, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Gorky, Maxim, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Hegel, Georg Wilhelm Friedrich and Richard Strauss, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Hopkins, Gerard M., undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Hugo, Victor, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Jowett, Benjamin, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Keats, John, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Lawrence, D. H., undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Mahler, Gustav, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Marx, Karl (1 of 4), undated (Box 7, Folder 22)